Personal Info

Name: Farouk Bakre

Address: Journalist Estate Phase 2, Arepo, Ogun, Nigeria.

Phone: +2348145251688

E-mail: faroukbakre@gmail.com

Website: https://www.faroukbakre.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/faroukbakre/

GitHub: https://github.com/Farbaks

Dribbble: https://dribbble.com/Farbaks

Creative software engineer with 3 years' experience participating in the complete software development lifecycle of successfully launched web and mobile applications. In previous roles, identified and resolved bottlenecks in codebase that optimized application performance by up to 20%; refactored mobile application codebase which increased efficiency and maintainability by 50%.

Experience

Frontend Developer - February 2021 - Present

Sudo Africa

- Developed a fully functional Online Banking Platform for Safe Haven Micro Finance Bank using Angular.
- Integrated new features into Sudo Africa Dashboard to allow easier and more efficient card and account control.

Software Engineer • December 2019 – February 2021

Serve Consulting Ltd.

- Refactored Clannit mobile application codebase from Ionic 3 to Ionic 5 to improve maintainability.
- Optimized performance across Clannit web application by up to 20% by Identifying and resolving bottlenecks.
- Provided support to users for Clannit web and mobile application (an application with over 10,000 active users); and Diagnosed and fixed issues on Clannit web application.

Software Developer • August 2018 – October 2018

New Usual Ltd.

- Developed a car repair web application, which provides hundreds of its users with real time car repair and towing services.
- Collaborated with software development team to implement new feature developments.

Education

2014 - 2019

Bells University of Technology B.Tech.,

Computer Science.

Skills

- JavaScript, jQuery, Typescript, React, Angular, NgRx, Electron, Vue, VueX, Nuxt, Ionic, Nodejs, Nestjs, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, GraphQL, Git, Heroku.
- Experience of writing and consuming REST APIs.
- Excellent communication skills.
- Analytical thinking and problem-solving capability.
- Fast learner.
- Creative thinker.